こいつは　まずいですよ    ただでさえ　ギリギリのところで
This is bad.
The defense was barely holding up before this.
防いでいるのに  カルロスまで出てきたら
If Carlos were to push further forward, we're done for.
ゼウベルトと　カルロス  攻撃の起点が２つになる
Zelberto and Carlos... They now have two points to initiate their attacks from.
来た～！
It's coming!
Listen up.
いいか  押さえるべきポイントは　ただ一つ
There is only one issue here.
Their best option... will be to pass the ball to Pepe.
頼みの綱　ぺぺへのパスコースだ
ぺぺだ！
It's Pepe!
ええいっ！
ホ　ホントに来た～！
Th-They really did it!
し　しまった！
Crap!
いくよ
I'm going.
えや～っ！
えい！　…あ
決まった～！
It's in!
しゃあ～！  椿～！
Tsubaki!
椿！　椿！　椿！　椿！
わ～！  やりやがったぞ　あの野郎！
That bastard actually scored!
That Tsubaki really has something in him!
やっぱり  椿のヤツは何か持ってる！
あいつの７番は  だてじゃねえ！
He's not the team's No.7 for nothing!
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ  風を受け止めて」
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ  たなびけ勝利のｆｌａｇ」
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
「遥かなゴールを信じて  走り続けて」
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
「日々夢紡ぐ者達へ  降り注げ光よ」
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
「汗は裏切らないって  唇噛み締め」
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
「何度も立ち上がり  大地を駆け抜ける」
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
「夢に終わりはないって  目を輝かせ」
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
「Ｌｅｔ’ｓ　ｓｔａｒｔ　ｎｏｗ  ＧＩＡＮＴ　ＫＩＬＬＩＮＧ」
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
「ｆｏｒ　ｔｈｅ　ｒｉｇｈｔ  ｈｏｌｄ　ｏｎ　ｔｉｇｈｔ」
For the right! Hold on tight!
「ｍｙ　ｓｔｏｒｙ…」
My story...
「ｆｏｒｅｖｅｒ」
Forever...
フリーだったんだよ！  俺はよ！　何で俺に出さないで
I was unmarked just now!
Why didn't you pass it to me?
わざわざ１人ついてる  ペペに出すんだよ！
Why did you pass it to Pepe who was clearly being marked?
なあおい　聞いてんのか　カルロス！  よせ
Are you listening, Carlos?!
Stop it.
Don't dwell on that incident anymore, Itagaki.
切り替えろ　板垣    ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
Don't screw with me!
What did Itagaki say just now?
Erm... Apparently you should have passed the ball to him instead?
くうう…
ここで　カルロスか！
Carlos again?
He's gonna shoot!
打ってくるぞ！
カルロス！
Carlos!
It's Pepe!
ペペだ！
ええいっ！
フリーでパスが来ないなんて  フォワードじゃねえ  　クソッ　クソッ　クソッ！
I was unmarked, yet they didn't pass it to me...
I'm not even considered a forward anymore.
Dammit!
もう左だとか右だとか  関係ねえ！　ゴール狙ってやる！
It has nothing to do with being on the right or left side anymore!
I'll just aim for the goal and shoot!
That should be the way.
That is how a forward should be.
椿　すごいじゃないか！
Tsubaki's excellent!
そうですね    私も驚いています
That's right.
I was surprised too.
あのスピードで　後ろから上がってくる  だけでも　大したものですが
He was able to move upfield with that kind of speed; that alone is very impressive...
まさか　ゴールまで決めるとは
But to think he could score too...
それに　この試合　椿は  ディフェンスでも　かなり効いています
Furthermore, Tsubaki's defending has been brilliant throughout the match.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ
1-0... Are we able to hold on till the end?
１対０か    逃げ切れるかね？
Who knows?
どうでしょう  　このまま何もなく  最後までいくとは思えません
I don't think we can maintain our advantage till the end though.
Then that's a problem!
それじゃ困るだろう
追いかける名古屋は　より  仕掛けてくると思いますが
I feel that Nagoya will regroup and try to equalize,
こちらも皆　集中力を切らさずに  ディフェンス　できています
but our players are concentrating and defending well.
The next goal...
次の１点…  次の１点が勝負だな
The next goal will be a crucial one.
Yeah.
はい
７番　よく動くな
No.7... He sure can run.
ヘイ！　カルロス！
Hey, Carlos!
残り１５分  　こじあけないと
Fifteen minutes left.
We have to find a way through!
ヘイ　よこせ！  時間がねえんだ！
Pass it to me!
Time's running out!
随分いい顔になってきたな
I like that expression on your face.
テメエなんか  相手じゃねえって言ったろ　板垣！
Didn't I make it clear that you can't beat me, Itagaki?!
チッ　うるせえ！  うるせえってんだよ！
Silence!
Shut up already!
シュートだ…　シュートを  打たねえと　ゴールは生まれねえ！
I have to shoot!
I won't score if I don't shoot!
打ってきた！
He took a shot!
They're starting to pile on their shots!
苦し紛れだ！  落ち着いて　コースふさげ！
Calm down and cover up the goal!
それだよ　板垣
That's it, Itagaki.
きれいに抜こうなんて  考えるな
Stop trying to take them on.
シュートを打たないフォワードなんて  怖くないんだ
No one will fear a striker who doesn't shoot.
セカンドボール！
The second ball!
Hey!
ヘイ！　ヘイ！
うっ…　ヤロッ！
Damn!
打ってやる  　打ってやるぜ！
Shoot!
I need to shoot!
だあっ！
くうう…　うあ～っ！
Very good, Itagaki.
いいぞ　板垣
ディフェンスにとって　一番　嫌なのは  常にゴールを意識しているフォワードだ
What annoys the defense the most... is someone who only has an eye for goal.
The Japanese hardly think like that.
日本人は　まだまだ  その意識が弱い
板垣　お前が  もう一つ上のレベルに上がり
Itagaki, if you're able to get yourself to the next level...
and be able to play in sync with the Brazilian Trio,
ブラジル人３人と  連係を深めることができれば
間違いなく　このチームの攻撃力は  リーグトップになる
This team will certainly have the best offense in the league.
ＥＴＵのような  小手先のカウンターサッカーなどに
We can't lose to a team like ETU, which uses tactics like counter-attacks.
負けるわけにはいかないのだ
Nice, Dori!
ナイス　ドリさん！
ドリ！　ドリ！  ドリ！　ドリ！
ドリ！　ドリ！　ドリ！  ドリ！　ドリ！　ドリ！
ライン　上げろ～！
Push the defense line up!
ふ～む
Alright!
よし！
えい！  いいぞ　椿！
Nice, Tsubaki!
ヘイ　ヘイ！
ヤロッ！
Damn!
I have to score this time!
次は決めてやる    見やがれ　俺の…
Take this!
ナイス　石浜！
Nice, Ishihama!
ハマさん！  椿！
Ishihama!
Tsubaki!
Forget it!
行かすか！
Go, Tsubaki!
いけ～　椿！
あ…　見える  　見える
I can see it.
I can see it!
見える  　ピッチも　ボールも
I can see it.
The pitch,
the ball,
サポーターも    すげえ　よく見える
even the fans...
I can see them clearly!
That kid...!
Wait, Zelberto! Mark No.10!
The opponent's attacks all go through No.10!
Carlos...
You prepare for the counter, Zelberto!
If you're coming at me directly, I'll definitely stop you.
このまま来るなら  僕が止めるよ
カルロス　止めろ～！
Stop him, Carlos!
Tsubaki... He's fast!
速えぞ　椿のヤツ
開け　世良！  チャンス　チャンス！
Find space, Sera!
This is our chance!
後ろも上がれ～！
Push up!
The coaches are yelling...
コーチたちが叫んでる    今までの試合じゃ
I was never able to notice it during the past matches.
目にも入らなかったのに    何でだろう？
Why?
Matches against the two top teams are special.
トップチームの試合ってのは  特別なもんだ
ビビリのお前が　慣れるのに時間が  かかっても　不思議じゃねえよ
A player like you would need long hours of practice to get used to them; that's no surprise.
That's right... Murakoshi mentioned it to me before.
そうだ…  村越さん　言ってくれたんだ
You should be able to see things that were previously oblivious to you.
見えなかったもんが  見えてくるかもしんねえぞ
少しは慣れたのかな…　俺
Am I starting to get used to it?
見えてくるものってのは  この景色なのかな
Things that are oblivious to me... Was he referring to this?
Go, Tsubaki!
行け～　椿！
カルロス！
Carlos!
Alright!
よ～し　行け　行け！  見せつけてやれ　椿
Go, go!
Let them see what you have, Tsubaki!
お前の才能を！
Your potential!
笑ってる
He's smiling?
何だと？
What?!
抜いた～！
He got past him!
止まんねえぞ　あいつ！
He's unstoppable!
Yeah, Tsubaki!
椿～！  来い！　来い！　来い！
Go! Go! Go!
カルロスが１回で  振り切られるなんて
He dribbled past Carlos with just one move!
何だよ　あいつ！
What's up with this guy?
No.10!
ディフェンス　当たれ～！
Defense, go!
Quit underestimating us!
なめんじゃねえよ！
あっ　２人！
Two of them!
ご苦労　バッキー
You did well, Baki.
Yes!!
Goal!!
Yeah!!
時間がないぞ～！  後ろも上がれ！
We're out of time!
Defense, push up!
Keep your focus guys! Concentrate!
集中するぞ！　集中！
今期　初勝利！
Our first win this season!
おら～！　見たかってんだ　不破！  だああ～！
Did you see that, Fuwa?!
たあ～っ！  やった～っ！
Yes!!
監督！
Manager!
Alright!
うしっ！
くうう…
ふぅ～…  ようやく１勝か
Finally, our first win.
数字の上じゃ  ただの勝ち星１つだろうが
Though it's still only 3 points,
we're able to suppress a rampant Nagoya and keep a clean sheet.
勢いのあった名古屋相手に零封だ    ディフェンス陣は自信をつけたはず
Our defense should be brimming with confidence now.
大きな１勝だと思うぜ　村越
This win is a giant step for us, Murakoshi.
分かってるよ　ドリさん
I know that, Dori.
ここからだ
It truly starts now.
ウチは　ここから巻き返す
We'll restore our former glory!
お疲れ！
Good work!
よう　俺の勝ちだな　板垣
Yo!
Looks like I've won this time, Itagaki.
テメエに負けたわけじゃねえ
I didn't lose to you.
ぬお？  負け惜しみか？　コラ！
What a sore loser!
今日の俺は  自滅したようなもんだ
My performance today is self-destructive.
腹くくって　もっと  がむしゃらに打ってかねえと
If I don't start giving it my all,
I could be warming the bench soon!
エースどころか  試合にすら出らんなくなんぞ
あの野郎  最後に守りづらくなりやがって
That bastard, he was hard to defend against towards the end.
ありがとう　達海君
Thank you, Tatsumi.
我々の完敗だ  　お陰で  今後の課題が　はっきり見えたよ
We lost convincingly.
Thanks to you, I was able to see the areas we need to rectify on.
ハハハ  　そいつは何より
That's good to know.
I'll see you at our next match, then.
では　またの対戦で
ウイ～ス  　さいなら～
Goodbye!
せいぜい調子に乗るがいい
Brag all you can now.
君たちにとっては  大きな１勝かもしれないが
To you people, this might be an important victory...
我々にとっては  リーグ戦の黒星１つにすぎない
But to us, it's just a blip.
Tactics that focus on the opponent's weaknesses...
相手のスキに  つけ込むような戦術
一発勝負のトーナメント戦なら  それで勝ち上がれても
only work in tournaments with knockout rounds.
It won't work in the league every time.
長いリーグ戦は　そうはいかない    結局　最後に　ものを言うのは
In the end, the score will be settled
フロントを含めたチームの総合力  チームとしての底力だ
by the team as a whole, including the management.
That is a team's true strength.
小手先サッカーのＥＴＵが  シーズン終盤に残っていられるか…
Can a superficial team like ETU survive by the end of the season?
If you're not going to accept the fact that you've lost,
負けた現実　受け入れねえと  また足元すくわれるぜ　不破さん
you might just slip and fall again embarrassingly one day, Fuwa.
What did he just say?
何だ？　何て言った？　今
ヘンッ！  どうしました？
What's wrong?
あんま　こたえてないみたい  だからさ  　別にそれならいいけど
It seems that he doesn't want to answer me.
Well, that's fine.
実際にやってみたら　向こうの  新たなスキも見えたし
Now that we've played, I've actually found other weaknesses in their team.
ウチの選手も　これから  伸びてくれそうだしね
Plus, it looks like our team will continue to grow from here on out.
I'm gonna trounce them the next time we play.
次やる時は  もっとコテンパンにしてやるよ
We won!
勝った  　…俺が出た  試合で　ゴールまで決めて…
We won a game with me in the team.
And I scored a goal too.
夢みたいだ
It's like a dream come true.
Found him!
Tsubaki, over here!
また来た！  何なの　この人たち？
They're back!
What is wrong with them?!
フウ
They look pretty pissed.
何か…　怒ってる？
それは　負けたから  機嫌悪いだろうけど…
Well, I guess it's natural for them to be mad after losing.
Tsubaki, I heard from Carlos.
You were enjoying yourself out there just now.
You were still smiling when you played.
言葉通じないとか  考えないのかな
Don't they realize that we can't understand each other?
Though we're upset with losing,
only those who enjoy their football the most will win.
フン    う…
You've earned our respect, Tsubaki.
You must be the one who enjoyed your football most today.
That's why...
We would like you to exchange jerseys with one of us!
Come, pick one!
Come!
あ…　え…　いや…
You're cunning, Pepe! Bribing him with curry bun...
How did you sneak that in here anyway?
They're scary!
怖い！　もう嫌だ
I've had enough!
え～？  僕じゃないんだ  　残念
What? It's not me? How sad.
Baki.
バッキー    え？  君だってさ
You're needed.
万歳！　万歳！  万歳！　万歳！
Hooray!
えっ　見ろよ　シゲちゃん！  今日のマンオブザマッチ　椿だよ！
Look at that, Shige!
Tsubaki's the Man of the Match today!
Well, he was the best player out there today...
確かに今日は　あいつだなぁ    いつもは頼りないけどよ
considering the fact that he's usually unreliable.
まずは　ゴールシーンを  振り返って頂きましょう
First, let's recall the first goal.
Erm... well. Uhh....
ええと…　あのう…
目の前にボールが転がってきて…  ええと…
The ball just happened to roll towards me...
はい    ええ…　なので
Yes?
So I had to do something...
触らなきゃって…    はい
Yes.
What was that? He's stuttering!
なんだ　ありゃ？  ガチガチじゃねえか
Tsubaki, though he's a totally different player from Tatsumi,
椿…　達海とは  全然違うタイプの選手だけど
he's still able to provide the same excitement!
あいつのプレーも  俺たちをワクワクさせてくれる！
シゲちゃん    うん？
Shige,
I'm going to do it.
俺　やるよ  　本気でやる！  ユウジも　カッちゃんも
I'm really going to do it.
Yuuji and Kacchan, let's do it!
本気でやろうぜ！　もう１回  仲間　集めて　本気でサポーターやろう！
Let's get the fans back, and reform our cheering team!
久堂さん　どうでした？
How was the match, Mr. Kudo?
うん？　…へへ　企業秘密
That's classified information.
Huh?
ふう    椿
Tsubaki.
ウス    あいさつ行ってこい
Yes?
Go and greet the fans.
椿！　椿！  椿！　椿！　椿！
椿！　椿！　椿！  椿！　椿！　椿！
ご苦労さん
Great work.
You've got find the way to believe
「Ｙｏｕ’ｖｅ　ｇｏｔ　ｆｉｎｄ  ｔｈｅ　ｗａｙ　ｔｏ　ｂｅｌｉｅｖｅ，  ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ　ａｎｄ　ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ」
Carry on and carry on
「Ｔｉｌｌ　ｙｏｕ　ｃａｎ　ｓｅｅ  ｔｏｍｏｒｒｏｗ，  Ｉ’ｌｌ　ｓａｙ　“ｎｅｖｅｒ　ｌｏｏｋ　ｂａｃｋ”」
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
「追い風を待って  そうｃｈａｎｃｅを  のがすなら」
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
「自分が風になれ　ｎｏ　ｆｅａｒｓ，  ｎｏ　ｔｅａｒｓ，　ｙｅｓ　Ｌｅｔ　ｉｔ　ｇｏ！」
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！）  Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
「限界追い越せ  行け　キツイほど  ｈｅａｒｔ　ｉｎ　ｒｅｄ」
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！  （Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！）  Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
「あすは見えない  だから」
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
「Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ  やめられない」
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！  Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！　Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！」
Get tough!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！）  Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
「共に乗り越えて　行け  見えるか　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｄａｙｂｒｅａｋ　ｔｈｅｒｅ」
mieruka It's daybreak there
見えるか It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！）　Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！  （Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）　予測できない」
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
「だから　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ  止められない」
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
The Edomae army is back!
Get the ball moving!
Go!
You're too slow!
We're still among the weakest.
This is not the time to get complacent!